Tara Prasad Mavanur Ramaprasad

Data Analyst

Experienced, enthusiastic and skilled Data Analyst. Abilities to assess data and translate results into actionable insights and a compelling narrative. Service oriented Customer Support Engineer, providing exceptional service and assistance to clients. Strong understanding and communication protocols. Super flexible in adapting to career journey.

tara.kadambi@gmail.com

9 82008, Unterhaching

in linkedin.com/in/tara-prasad-17582513

github.com/Tarakadambi

+4915168735923

tarakadambi.github.io/Tarakadambi.github/

facebook.com/tara.kadambi

(c) instagram.com/Tara.Kadambi

WORK EXPERIENCE

Analyst (Operations)

Indian Bank Singapore(Investment Bank)

11/2017 - 03/2018

Singapore

Achievements/Tasks

- Assisted in the development of standard operating procedures to maintain consistency and accuracy across all tasks.
- Facilitated smooth communication between departments by acting as a liaison when necessary, ensuring timely information exchange.
- Analyzed and reported on operational data to identify trends and issues.
- Promptly addressed customer inquiries and complaints to foster swift resolution

Temp Admin

Prosper Coal and Energy Pte Itd Singapore

04/2017 - 09/2017

Child Care

Workplace/Company

01/2010 - 03/2017

Customer support Executive.

RiverVale Walk RC Singapore

01/2008 - 12/2009

Singapore

- Achievements/Tasks
- Skilled at working independently and collaboratively in a team environment.
- Developed strong communication and organised events.
- Delivered services to customers within specific time frames.
- Used strong analytical and problem-solving skills to develop effective solutions for challenging situations.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

Customer Support Assistant

ICICI Bank Singapore(Investment Bank)

08/2005 - 05/2006

Singapore

Achievements/Tasks

- Assessed satisfaction levels after problem resolution ensuring clients expectations were met. Worked under Relationship Manager.
- Managed a high volume of customer tickets, maintaining organization and prioritizing urgent cases. Web trading..
- Responded to customer inquiries and provided technical assistance over phone and in person.
- Participated in regular team meetings to discuss ongoing challenges, share insights, and collaborate on continuous improvement initiatives.
- Worked on database with our Mumbai(India) HQ team. Streamlined communication channels for faster response times and improved customer experience.

SKILLS

SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)

ableau

Business Operations

Power BI

Pytho

Excel (Tables, Charts, dashboards)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Python: Performed data cleaning and manipulation. EDA using pandas, matplotlib, NumPy and seaborn Libraries.

1.Festival_Sales_report:

- Tarakadambi/Python_Festival (github.com)
- 2. Student Analysis:
- <u>Tarakadambi/Python_StudentAnalysis (github.com)</u>
- 3.Wine Analysis-:
- Tarakadambi/Python_wine-Datasets (github.com)
- 4. Music-data analysis:
- Tarakadambi/python_music_data (github.com)

Power BI; 1.Bank Churn :Validated/created Dashboard for Bank churn customer using Power BI.

- PowerBI/BankChurn_project.new.pdf at main · Tarakadambi/PowerBI (github.com)
- 2. Financial analysis- Datasets from Kaggle datasets. Analysis on Power BI(KPI n DAX).
- Tarakadambi/Financial-Power-BI (github.com)

SQL: used few SQL commands on MySQL workbench.

 library/indexlib.html at master · Tarakadambi/library (github.com)

Excel Dashboard: Using Pivot table and charts created dashboard and analyze.

 test_ods/project store_ods.1.pdf at main · Tarakadambi/test_ods (github.com)

Tableau:

 Built report on dash boards for airline data and covid-data study with Tableau

Tara Prasad Mavanur Ramaprasad

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manual Tester

Pacific IT Solutions Bangalore, India

04/2007 - 09/2007

Bengaluru, India

OTHER PROJECTS

Manual Software Testing- Open Cart e-commerce Platform.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Bachelor of Engineering: Industrial Production Jawaharlal Nehru National College Of Engineering. Karnataka, India.

Karnataka, India

CERTIFICATES

SKILLUP

Courses

- Data Science with Python
- Business Analytics
- Tableau Training
- Power BI

German Language Integration Course B1

VHS - Unterhaching, Germany

Munich

CERTIFICATE- Software Testing

System Domain

Bengaluru, India

Courses

Software Tool Testing

German Language - B2

Anderwerk.de (Online)

Munich

Courses

 Course Completed. (I am about to take B2- Exam shortly)

SKILLS AND COMPETENCE



ACHIEVEMENTS

* Winner of International yoga quiz competition 2020 organized by Indian Council for Cultural Relations, Munich

*Voluntary Service Award 2016 by RC Singapore - GO GREEN Singapore - Presented by MP Michael Palmer

FÜHRERSCHEIN

Klasse B

LANGUAGES

German – B1 Level(B2- Course Completed)

Limited Working Proficiency

Tamil - Advanced Level Full Professional Proficiency

Kannada – Native Speaker Full Professional Proficiency

English - Advanced Level Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi – Advance level Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Travelling

Gardening

Music